Hey. Aron here, leave a message.
嘿 这是Aron家 有事请留言
Hi Aron, Sonja here... again.
嗨 Aron 又是我... Sonja
I know that you're probably gonna be away this weekend, but...
我知道你这周末可能要出去 但...
listen, think about what we are gonna play.
想想我们要弹什么吧
Please, just we have to decide, we really... we need to practice, OK?
得快点决定下来 我们... 得先排练一下 好吗?
Anyway it will be fun, I promise.
总之 我保证会很有意思的
And... oh, please call mom, please. Because she worries...
还有... 哦 给妈打个电话吧 她总担心...
which you knew already. OK, later A, bye.
你知道的 我不多说了 A 回聊 拜拜
下一个服务站 100英里
Hey. It's Friday night.
嘿 现在是周五晚上
April 25, 2003.
2003年4月25日
I'm just entering Canyonlands.
我刚进入峡谷地国家公园
Just me, the music and the night.
就只有我 听着音乐享受这夜晚
Love it.
爱死了
星期六
Blue John Canyon.
到Blue John峡谷了
Guidebook says: 4.5 hours until the Big Drop.
旅行指南上面写: 到Big Drop还要四个半小时
I aim to take 45 minutes off that.
我打算提前45分钟到达
I don't know, I think we should go that way.
不知道 我觉得我们该往那边走
And if we proceed that way, then we need to come back...
我们再往那边走的话 一会还得回来...
You're doing Blue John too, huh?
你们也在Blue John峡谷玩呢?
No, actually, we were headed for the Dome.
不是 我们想去Dome
- But I think we are lost.  - She's lost.
- 但好像迷路了  - 她迷路了
Hang on.
等着
Let's see this.
我看看
- You are... here.  - We are?
- 你们现在... 在这  - 是吗?
I knew that.
我就知道
And the Dome is there.
Dome在那边
I can take you that way if you like.
你们愿意的话 我可以带你们去
Sorry, Friday the 13th there. Not a killer.
不好意思 忘了摘面罩 挺恐怖的吧(《13号星期五》电影中的杀人狂也戴面罩)
I'm only a psychopath on weekdays. It's Saturday, so...
我工作日时才是变态 现在周六 所以...
I can't take this off. It's my face.
这是我的脸 摘不下的
- Aron.  - Kristi.
- 我叫Aron  - 我是Kristi
Allow me to introduce you to my friend Megan.
这是我朋友Megan
- Nice to meet you.  - It's an honor.
- 很高兴认识你  - 很荣幸
What do you say? You're lost, I am the guide, OK?
你们说呢? 你们迷路了 我当你们导游 好吗?
- Why not?  - Sure.
- 有什么关系呢?  - 当然好
All right. This way.
好的 咱们上路了
So you biked from Horseshoe? Is that like 20 miles?
你从Horseshoe那儿骑车来的? 大概有20英里远吧?
17 on the odometer.
里程表上显示的是17英里
Oh, I thought it was 17.2.
我还以为会是17.2英里呢
17.3. Actually.
其实是17.3英里
Ah, You're one of those.
啊 你是那种单车一族吧
- Not one of those.  - Do you spend a lot of time out here?
- 不算是  - 你经常来这吗?
It's my second home.
这儿是我第二个家
See? There's the fork right there.
看到了吧? 就是这条岔路
- We totally missed that.  - Glad we bumped into you.
- 我们完全没看见  - 还好碰见你了
- What are the odds considering we're all the way out here?  - Exactly.
- 从这么老远来 能碰见真是太巧了  - 就是啊
You're in the one place in America.
你们在美国某地
You're pretty much guaranteed not to run into a weirdo.
本以为不可能碰见什么怪人的
But what happened?
但你看发生了什么?
All right. So the guidebook says...
旅行指南书说...
that the route is through here... but I know a better way.
应该从这穿过去... 但我知道一条更好的路
The cool way.
给力的路
Guaranteed, the best time you can have with your clothes on.
我向你们保证 这肯定会是你们一生中最棒的经历 而无须脱衣
Although, it's better with your clothes off.
当然了 把衣服脱了更好
- It is a bit of a climb.  - We climb.
- 可能需要爬点山  - 我们很能爬的
- And a bit of a squeeze.  - We squeeze.
- 可能会有点挤  - 我们不在乎挤
So you get us all the way fucking here
你把我们一路带到这种烂地儿
and then you tell us you're not a guide...
才告诉我们你不是个导游...
Well no, I'm an engineer.
我不是 我是个工程师
But this is what I really want to do.
但导游才是我的理想职业
That's wonderful. Hey, I... I always wanted to be a supermodel, but...
真棒 我一直想当个超模 但是...
I don't think that's really gonna work, you know?
我不觉得我真能当上
Jesus. What if these things move?
天哪 要是这些东西动了怎么办?
They've been here for millions of years. They're not gonna move.
他们都在这呆了几百万年了 不会动的
- Oh sure they will.  - What?
- 他们当然会动啦  - 什么?
Yeah, everything's moving all the time. Let's just hope not today.
一切都是瞬息万动的 只希望不是今天动喽
Great.
太好了
All right, all you've got to remember, is that everything will be okay.
你们要记住一点 一切都会没事的
Oh, oh my God!
哦 天哪!
Aron, are you okay? Aron?
Aron 你还好吗? Aron?
Aron?
Aron呢?
Listen to the guy, he's fine.
听啊 他没事
He is bad shit. You're bad shit!
他太坏了 你这个坏人!
Come on. You've gotta come down here.
快跳吧 快下来看看
- Trust me.  - Trust you? I'll kill you Aron Ralston.
- 相信我  - 相信你? 我要杀了你 Aron Ralston
Oh, please, you love this.
哦 别废话了 你爱冒险的
Nice job!
真不错!
- Megan, you're missing it.  - It's amazing.
- Megan 别错过了  - 很棒的
- Fuck.  - Just jump, Megan.
- 操  - Megan 快跳吧
- Are you okay?  - Nice job.
- 你还好吧?  - 不错啊
- We've got to do it again.  - Again?
- 我们要再跳一次  - 再来?
- Camera.  - Camera.
- 录下来  - 录下来 好的
So, Blue John...
话说 Blue John峡谷...
is actually named after this guy Blue John who was Butch Cassidy's cook.
其实是以Butch Cassidy的厨师的名字命名的
From Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid.
就是 《虎豹小霸王》(经典西部影片)里的
And they would hide out in these canyons, I guess,
我猜他们曾藏在这些峡谷中
but also what they do is they run horses, wild horses into here
他们还把野马赶进来
and trap them at the end of the canyon...
把它们困在峡谷底...
and that's how they catch the horses.
以这种方式抓马
- Hey, would you take another picture before I go?  - Yeah.  - OK, cool.
- 嘿 我走之前能和你们再合张影么?  - 当然了  - 那好
Ready?
准备好了么?
One, two, three... Blue John
3 2 1... 于Blue John留念
Will I ever see you again?
我们还能再见吗?
That depends, do you party?
那得看你参不参加聚会了
Do I party? Yes, sometimes.
聚会? 我有时参加
Tomorrow night we're actually, seriously, throwing a party,
明晚 我们还真的要办一个聚会
if you want to come.
你要是愿意 也可以来
Yeah, you should come by to have a beer and kick back.
是啊 过来喝点啤酒 放松一下
OK, where am I going?
好啊 在哪儿?
It's about 20 miles away, near Green River.
离这儿20英里左右吧 绿河附近
You know the old motel, it's behind that.
你肯定认得那个旧汽车旅馆 就在它后面
There's gonna be a huge inflatable Scooby-Doo. Can't miss it.
到时候那会有个巨大的充气史酷比 你肯定能找到
- Really? Okay. Cool.  - OK.
- 真的吗? 好 很酷  - 好吧
- It's good to meet you. See you.  - Bye.
- 很高兴认识你们 再见  - 拜拜
Scooby-Doo.
是史酷比哦
Yeah. Rock on.
记住了 继续前行
You think he's actually gonna show up?
你觉得他真的会来吗?
I don't think we figured in his day at all.
我们怎么可能预测他的行为
You liked him.
你心动了吧
This is insane.
太他妈操蛋了
Move! This fucking rock.
妈的 石头 快给我动!
Please.
求你了
Kristi! Megan!
Kristi! Megan! 你们在哪儿!
Kristi! It's Aron!
Kristi! 我是Aron!
Megan!
Megan啊!
Just think.
动动脑子
Fuck.
操
Shit!
妈的!
Sweet.
太好了
Knife's dull.
刀太钝了
星期天
Look at the size of this. How the fuck did this get here?
这石头太他妈大了 它是怎么到这的啊?
Hi, buddy.
嗨 小鬼
Here we go.
我们走咯
It's 03:05.
现在是3点05分
Sunday, April 27, 2003.
2003年4月27日 周日
This marks 24 hours...
我被困在Blue John峡谷里...
of being stuck in Blue John Canyon.
已经整整一天了
Right where it's just before the Big Drop.
具体方位就在Big Drop前面一点
My name is Aron Ralston. My parents are...
我叫Aron Ralston 我的父母是...
Donna and Larry Ralston.
Donna Ralston和Larry Ralston
From Englewood Colorado.
他们住在Englewood Colorado
Whoever finds this, can keep the recorder...
不管谁找到这个 你可以拿走录像机...
but please try to get in touch with my parents and give them this tape.
但请试着联系我父母 把这盘带子给他们
I would appreciate it.
我会十分感激的
I was descending Blue John yesterday...
我昨天在Blue John峡谷往下走...
when this chalkstone came loose...
这块白垩石突然松动...
and rolled onto my arm.
滚到了我的手臂上
Now it's stuck.
现在它被卡住了
This arm is... has this gray-blue color.
这只手臂... 变成了灰蓝色
It's been without circulation for 24 hours.
其内血液停止流动已经一天
So... I think it's pretty well gone.
所以... 我觉得它差不多已经坏死了
I'm low on food.
我食物快吃完了
That's about 300-400 ml.
这有差不多300到400毫升吧
And that's it for water.
水就剩这么多
I'm in pretty deep doo here.
可以说现在状况很惨淡
Hello?
有人吗?
Please, there's somebody down here.
求你了 有人在下面
Help! I am in the Canyon.
救救我! 我在峡谷里面
Please, help!
求你了 救我!
Help!
救命啊!
Down here. Help!
我在峡谷里 救命啊!
Don't lose it.
别慌
Aron...
Aron 你听着...
Do not lose it.
一定要稳住
Not bad.
还不错嘛
Dinner.
该吃晚饭了
Tomorrow night we're actually, seriously throwing a party, if you want to come.
明天晚上我们真的要办一个聚会 你要是愿意 也可以来
Yeah you should come by to have a beer and kick back.
是啊 过来喝点啤酒 放松一下
There's gonna be a huge inflatable Scooby-Doo.
到时候会有个巨大的充气史酷比
Scooby-Doo.
史酷比
Cold cans.
冻汽水罐
Plastic cup.
塑料杯
Thank you.
谢谢
Can I take a beer?
我能拿瓶啤酒么?
Won't mind if I do.
应该不会介意的吧
Aron here, leave a message.
这是Aron家 有事请留言
Aron, it's mom.
Aron 我是妈妈
I was hoping to catch you.
我想跟你说点事
Are you there? Hello?
你在家吗? 有人吗?
Okay. Nothing urgent.
好吧 也没什么急事
Doug is in New York. So it will be a quiet weekend.
Doug在纽约呢 所以这周末清闲下来了
Call me, OK?
记得回电话 好吗?
- Where are you going?  - Don't know yet.
- 你要去哪?  - 还不知道呢
Right there, Brian.
Brian 我就去这里
Maybe Utah, maybe somewhere else.
也许去犹他州 也许去别的地方
- Have a good one.  - Always do.
- 旅行愉快  - 我会的
Let's go.
开始了
星期一
It's freaking me out looking at myself.
看我自己这个样子太抓狂了
Sorry, hope that's okay.
抱歉 希望你别介意
It's Monday.
现在周一了
Bummer, all day. I tried to set up this pulley.
一整天都很衰 我试着组装一个简易滑轮
All morning. But it did not work.
用了整个上午 还是没用
It was worth a try, but there is too much friction,
值得一试 但摩擦力太大了
it's climbing rope, so there's too much stretch.
这是根攀岩绳 张力太大
What I could use is 20 meters of static rope...
我需要20米长的静力绳(不会或很少伸长的绳子)...
9.8 millimeters.
直径要9.8毫米的
Three or four pulleys, rack of carabiners, a sling, powerdrill...
三四个滑轮 一些吊钩 一根吊索 一个机械钻...
and Pull Kit.
还有一个牵引器
And eight burly men to do the hawling.
再来八个强壮的男人把它拽上去
That should just about do it.
这样就差不多可以了
Another 150ml of water left.
还剩150毫升水
That should keep me alive till tomorrow night.
应该能使我撑到明晚
If I'm lucky. I peeded twice.
前提是我够幸运 我撒了两次尿
Almost pissed my pants.
差点尿到裤子上了
My body's acting really wierd.
身体有点不听使唤
The second time I did it in the CamelBak.
第二次的时候我尿到CamelBak水袋里了
It smells really bad.
太难闻了
But I'm sure it'll settle.
但尿液肯定会变澄清的
It's gotta be chilled, like Sauvignon Blanc.
得放冷一些 就像白索维农(一种白葡萄酒)一样
No number twos.
没有解大手
Which should disappoint my insect friends.
我的昆虫朋友们可要失望了
They'll just have to wait.
它们得再等等
Let's see, what else can I tell you?
我看看 还有什么能说的?
There is this raven that comes every morning.
有只渡鸦每天早上都飞过
I clocked it at 08:17.
我记了下时间 8点17分
I'll film it for you tomorrow.
明天我会拍下它
Every morning at 09:30 I get fifteen minutes of sunlight.
每天早上9点30我能晒到15分钟太阳
It's really nice.
特别舒服
I've been chipping away.
我一直在削这块石头
More to keep warm than anything.
除了保暖 别无他求
I'm beginning to think that my hand is supporting the rock.
我开始想 是我的手在支撑这块石头
So what if I chip away a bit, it actually settles more.
所以有可能我削得越多 手就被压得更紧
I've found this great tourniquet.
我找到了特别适合做止血带的东西
It hasn't been very useful.
没什么用
Listen! Don't buy the cheap made-in-China multitool.
听着! 千万别买便宜的中国刀具
I tried to find my Swiss Army knife, but...
我当初找过我的瑞士军刀 可没找到
This thing came free with a flashlight.
这东西是买手电筒附赠的
The flashlight was a piece of shit too.
那手电筒也是废物一个
I kept it in my truck for emergencies.
我把它放在车里应急
I don't blame you, Mom.
我不怪你 妈妈
It was a perfectly great stocking stuffer.
这是个很好的圣诞礼物
No way you could have ever known I'd get in this kind of trouble.
你也想不到有一天我会陷入这种麻烦
When we watch this later, the camera has to be turned on?
我们一会看这录像的时候 得先把录像机打开是吗?
- Am I right?  - Yeah.
- 是吗?  - 是的
You have to leave the camera with us
要是你想让我们看你拍的东西
when we wanna see something that you've made, right?
你就得把录像机留给我们 对吗?
Good job, Hon.
干得好 女儿
- That is really beautiful.  - He's filming her now.
- 真优美  - 他现在在拍她
We can show this?
我们从这能看见?
Go away.
走开啦
We can't just watch it over there.
我们在那就看不见了
Well done.
弹得很棒
Way to go, sis.
加油 妹妹
- Keep playing?  - Yes honey, keep going.
- 还要弹吗?  - 继续吧 宝贝
I love you.
我爱你
So...
那么...
how do I get in?
我怎么进去?
What is the...
那个...
you know, combination?
密码是什么?
If I told you...
我告诉你之前...
I'd have to kill you.
我得先杀了你
But you've already killed me.
可你已经夺走了我的心
Combination? I think I have it.
密码吗? 我知道了
Fuck.
靠
Who's there?
谁啊?
Aron?
Aron吗?
Please.
求你了
帮帮我
星期二
Good morning, everyone.
大家早上好
It is seven o'clock here in Canyonlands USA.
现在是早上七点整 我在美国峡谷地国家公园
This morning, on the boulder, we have a very special guest:
今天早上 位于岩石上 我们有位特别嘉宾:
self-proclaimed american superhero...
自称美国超级英雄的...
Aron Ralston. Let's hear it for Aron.
Aron Ralston 欢迎Aron
Goshes! It is a real pleasure to be here. Thank you. Thanks.
天哪! 很荣幸来到这里 谢谢 谢谢大家
Can I say hi to my mom and dad?
我能问候下我爸我妈吗?
Mom and Dad. Mustn't forget Mom and Dad. Right, Aron?
爸妈总是第一位的 Aron 对吧?
Yeah, that's right.
是啊
Hi mom, I'm really sorry I didn't answer the phone the other night.
嗨 妈妈 真对不起那天晚上没回你电话
If I had, I would have told you where I was going and then...
要是回了 我就会告诉你我要前往何处...
- I probably wouldn't be here right now.  - That's for sure.
- 那我现在也许就不会被卡在这了  - 那是肯定的啦
But like I always say...
但就像我常说的...
Your supreme selfishness is our gain.
你的自私自利是我们快乐的源泉
Thank you, Aron. Anyone else you'd like to say hi to?
谢谢你 Aron 你还想向谁打招呼吗?
- Brian, at work.  - Hi, Aron.
- 我同事Brian  - 嗨 Aron
I probably won't be making it in to work today.
我今天可能上不了班了
Get a load of this guy. Wait. Hold on.
哟 大家快听听 等下 别挂断
We got a question coming in from another Aron...
有个来自犹他州失败者峡谷的Aron...
in Loser Canyon, Utah.
想问你个问题
Aron asks: Am I right in thinking...
他问道: 是不是就算你同事Brian向警方汇报了...
that even if Brian from work notifies the police...
他们也得再等个一天
they'll put a 24-hour hold on it
才能发一份失踪人口报告出来
before they file a missing persons report?
Aron 是这样吗?
Which means you won't become officially missing...
那么也就是说 最早也得在周三中午之前...
until midday Wednesday at the earliest.
你才算是在案的失踪人口
You're right on the money there, Aron.
是啊 你说到点子上了 Aron
Which means, I'll probably be dead by then.
这意味着 那时候我估计都死了
Aron from Loser Canyon, Utah.
来自犹他州失败者峡谷的Aron
- How do you know so much?  - Well, I will tell you why I know so much.
- 你怎么这么清楚?  - 我来告诉你为什么
I volunteer for a little rescue service.
我当过救援小组的志愿者
You see, I'm something of a, big fucking hard hero.
其实 我算是一个牛逼的英雄人物
I can do everything on my own, you see?
我什么都能自己搞定 看出来了么?
I do see.
我确实看出来了
Is it true that despite ..
是不是尽管...
or maybe because you're a fucking hard hero...
或者说也许正因为你是个牛逼的英雄人物...
you didn't tell anyone where you were going?
所以你没把你的去向告诉任何人?
Yeah, that's absolutely correct.
是啊 就是这样
- Anyone?  - Anyone.
- 没人知道?  - 没人
Oops.
你悲剧咯
Mom, Dad...
爸 妈...
I just wanna take this time to tell you that,
我想用剩下的这点时间来告诉你们
the times we've spent together were awesome...
我们在一起的那些日子很美好...
and I haven't appreciated you in my heart as I know that I could.
我却没有全心全意去珍惜它们
Mom, I love you...
妈 我爱你...
and I wish I had returned all your calls...
我真希望我每次都给你回电话了...
Ever.
每一次
I love you guys.
我爱你们
And I'll always be with you.
我会一生一世在你们身边
Wednesday
星期三
This is no Slurpy.
一点都不像思乐冰(一种碳酸饮料)
It's like a bag of piss.
喝起来就是一包尿
OK, I'm gonna go up again.
我再上去一次
Great one.
真棒
- Listen.  - We can tell you more. OK.
- 听着  - 我们再告诉你件事
- Tell him.  - We are very worried about you.
- 快说  - 我们很担心你
- We're worried about your music.  - An advice for your choice of music.
- 我们对你的音乐品位表示担忧  - 给你个选择音乐的小建议
If you keeps singing "Fish Are Really Rock"...
要是你还继续唱 "Fish Are Really Rock" 这首歌...
then you never get a girlfriend.
你就永远找不到女朋友了
- Never.  - You may have one but I really doubt it.
- 永远找不到  - 也许能有一个 不过我对此表示怀疑
You're maybe sort of cute.
你挺可爱的
- Occationally.  - Occationally.
- 有时候了  - 只是有时候
OK, this cannon ball is for you.
好了 给你表演个抱膝跳水
I'm going to test your theory about whether or not it's better...
我准备验证一下你的理论...
with or without clothes on.
看看到底是穿上衣服还是脱了衣服好
Don't.
别
Please, don't.
千万要忍住
- Don't.  - Ralston, rock on.
- 忍住  - Ralston 你真牛
You don't even want me here, do you?
你都不想让我呆在这了 是吗?
I'm gonna go, Aron.
我要走了 Aron
Is that what you want?
这就是你想要的吧?
It is, isn't it?
就是这样吧?
Okay.
那好
Come back.
回来啊
You're gonna be so lonely, Aron.
Aron 你会无比孤单的
46, 47, 48, 49...
四十六 四十七 四十八 四十九...
50! And here I am! I'm coming.
五十! 我要来了!
I'm holding on.
我还在坚持
Time's moving really slowly.
时间过得太慢了
My heart's beating really fast. I swear to God, it feels like it...
我的心脏跳得特别快 我向上帝发誓 感觉它的...
it's beating three times as fast as it should be.
速度是正常时候的三倍
So cold.
我很冷
Blue John?
你是Blue John吗?
I love you.
我爱你
Rana, I've been thinking about you, girl.
Rana 我一直在想你
I know how I am. I've tried to do everything. Whatever it was...
我知道自己现在状态很差 我什么都试过了 任何方法...
- I tried.  - Aron, where are you?
- 我都试过了  - Aron 你在哪呢?
What are you guys doing here? Andy.
你们怎么在这? Andy
Tom. Hi, guys. What's going on?
Tom 你们好啊 怎么了?
- Aron.  - Hey.
- Aron  - 嘿
You look like the Hole in the Wall Gang.
你们看起来就像 "Hole in the Wall Gang" (北爱尔兰喜剧小组)的成员
Dorks.
一群傻瓜
Found you Aron.
找到你了 Aron
Sis, I'm sorry that I won't be at your wedding.
妹妹 对不起 我不能参加你的婚礼了
I know that I promised to play.
我知道我保证过要弹钢琴的
That we play.
是我们一起弹
I'm sorry. I know it'll be a good one.
对不起 婚礼一定会很完美的
8:15, there's no raven. 8:20...
八点一刻了 渡鸦还没来 八点二十了...
I think that my raven didn't come.
我觉得那只渡鸦不会来了
I've been thinking.
我一直在想
Everything...
所有事...
- just comes together.  - You're gonna be so lonely, Aron.
- 都集中到一起了  - Aron 你会无比孤单的
- Have a good one.  - Always do.
- 旅行愉快  - 我会的
- Later!  - It' me.
- 回见!  - 是我
Aron, it's mom.
Aron 我是妈妈
- I was hoping to catch you.  - I chose this.
- 我想和你说点事  - 是我自己导致的
Doug is in New York. So it'll be a quiet weekend.
Doug在纽约呢 所以这周末清闲下来了
- I chose all of this.  - Call me.
- 是我自己导致了这一切  - 记得回电话
This rock...
这块石头...
this rock has been waiting for me my entire life.
这块石头足足等了我一辈子
I hate this rock!
我恨这块石头!
And its entire life. Ever since it was a bit of meteorite.
从它还是一丁点的陨石开始 它便用尽一生来等待我
A million billion years ago.
从一千万亿年之前就开始了
How the fuck did this get here?
这他妈的怎么到这来的?
There in space. It's been waiting...
从宇宙中来 它就等待着...
to come here.
来到这里
Right, right here.
这个地方 这个位置
I've been moving towards it my whole life. The minute I was born.
我的一生都在朝它走来 从我出生的那一刻起
Every breath I've taken, every action...
我的每次呼吸 所做的每件事...
has been leading me to this. A crack on the earth surface.
都在引领我来这儿 这个地缝里
Come on.
坚持住
Don't pass out.
别晕过去
Thank you.
谢谢这一切
Easy.
放轻松
Easy. Come on.
放轻松 没事的
Help me.
救救我
I need help.
救命啊
I need some water. I was stuck in a crack.
我要喝水 我被卡在岩缝里了
Some water, please. I cut my arm off.
给我点水 求你了 我截断了我的手臂
Please, some water.
求你了 给我点水
Thank you.
谢谢
- Do you have a phone?  - Yes, but no signal.
- 你带电话了吗?  - 带了 但是没信号
- You should stop and rest.  - No.
- 你该停下来歇歇  - 不用
I better keep going.
我得继续走
Will you run? Will you run ahead?
你们跑吧 往前跑好吗?
Aron's premonition came true.
预兆成为了现实
He met his wife Jessica three years later.
3年后Aron遇见了他的妻子Jessica
Their son, Leo, was born in February 2010.
2010年2月份 他们的儿子Leo出生了
Aron continued to be a climber and canyoneer.
Aron继续他的攀登和峡谷冒险事业
He always leaves a note to say where he has gone.
不同的是 他总会留个便条告诉家人他去哪了
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://bbs.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调：专采油菜花
翻译：Uriana
校对：甜蜜的向往